hey guys this looks like a fun one we're
trying to find the area of
ACF so that's the area of this reddish
triangle we're also given that this is a
rectangle and that ABC which is this
triangle is congruent to a e c which is
this triangle up here so these two are
congruent as well if you want to try it
on your own pause it right now because
I'm going to solve it in 3 21 so how do
we approach this I'm just going to go
freestyle and try to find everything I
can first thing I'm noticing is this
right triangle so we can make this side
C and do Pythagorean theorem we have 3^2
+ 4^2 is equal to c^ 2 32 is equal to 9
4 2 is equal to 16 and then we can bring
down the c^ 2 9 + 16 is equal to 25 so
we have 25 is equal to c^2 to solve for
C we can square root both sides square >
of 25 is 5 and square < TK of c^2 is C
so now we figured out that this C is
equal to 5 and we can give it a label of
meters to match these other ones what
should we do do next okay I know what to
do next in a rectangle opposite sides
are congruent so this side is also equal
to four ABC is congruent to a e c this
order of these letters is very important
since the first two letters of this are
ab and the first two letters of this are
AE we know side AB is congruent to side
AE so we know that this AB is equal to
AE which means we can label that as 4 M
and we also know since the second letter
is B and this second letter is e that
angle B is equal tole angle e so since
angle B is a right angle that means this
angle e is also a right angle these
congruent triangles gave us quite a bit
of info next let's focus on these two
triangles this angle and this angle are
both congruent because they're vertical
angles and now we know that angle AF is
congruent to cfd that's what we just
found with the vertical angles we know
that angle e is equal to angle D because
they're both right and we know that AE
is congruent to CD because they're both
equal to four therefore we can conclude
that these two triangles are congruent
and that's using the angle angle side
theorem any two triangles where we have
a corresponding angle angle and a side
those two triangles have to be congruent
and now we have another congruent
statement so looking at these first two
letters and these first two letters we
know the segment AF is equal to segment
CF that means this AF is equal to this
CF and since we know CF is five that
means we know this is five and now we're
pretty much done let's get rid of this
stuff and if you look at our red
triangle we have a base and we have a
height and give me a second I'll make
this easier to see so there we go now we
can see the base is five and the height
is four and if it's easier we can flip
this so here's the base of five and the
height of four the area of a triangle is
equal to 1/2 base time height we can
plug in five for the base and plug in
four for the height and 1/2 * 5 * 4 is
equal to 10 so the area of this red
triangle is 10 m squar this is the
answer to our question let's put a box
around around it and here's the next
problem I'm going to work on I'll post
the video as soon as I finish how
exciting